We'll be nice. We'll give Paul a little bit of time.
There she is. Excellent.
Okay, so we are all here. We are going to call to order the
regular Board of Selectmen meeting for Monday, 11/08/2021,
and we are going to start with the Pledge of Allegiance.
I pledge allegiance to the flag
The United States Of America and to the Republic for which it stands,
one nation
under God,
indivisible,
with liberty and justice for all. Okay.
Public speak.
We'll
start with Diane Greiner.
I'm all set. Thank you. Okay.
Diane Choquette.
I am all set.
>> Okay.
Kathy and Mike Palazzi.
We are all set, thank you. All right, good to hear from you.
Thanks.
Kimberly Persson.
I'm all set, thank you. Okay, Jeff Murray has joined us, we're all here.
Home
can't read that, 20. Home tool 20.
Would you like to participate in public speak?
Since that's a no, we're going to move on to additions and deletions to the agenda. Do we have any additions to the agenda?
>> So, I'm going to suggest we add item G,
and I would call that the Carko field evaluation
services.
>> So
new business 10
gs, what do you want to do with this?
Just,
Mr. Clarko Field Evaluation
Services.
>> Isn't that 10D, the Veterans Memorial Field Funding and Agreement? What is that?
No.
Well, it could be.
>> Why don't we just add it to that, Eric? Okay, that's fine too. Tendi, we'll call it
>> triple I.
Okay,
I can't even spell. There we go.
Somebody's gonna have to make that motion, but is anybody else? Adrian, do you have anything you want to add? I do not.
Paula?
Okay. Scott?
I'm fine.
Jeff Murray?
>> He's probably driving. We don't wanna sit there and cause a crash.
So if he's not gonna add anything, I think
I talked to him. I talked to him. He didn't have anything. Alright, so I'll make a motion that we add to 10 D item three
Calarco
field maintenance
agreement.
Alright, who wants to second that? Second.
All right, all those in favor? Aye.
All those opposed?
Okay, all those who abstain?
Mr. Murti abstained,
so it passes.
All right, we're going to move on to item four, the finance director presentation
on new financial software.
Sherri Holmes, the town treasurer has joined us.
>> Hi, Sherri. Hi, good evening.
Edmunds,
new financial software system.
I feel it's going well.
We are
fully up and running at this point.
The last
bit of training
happened today with the bank statements. It's still going to continue.
We got a little bit of overview
of
what the bank reconciliation
looks like and what it how it is functioning.
So I feel we're going to need a little bit more training on that as we go through it.
But as far as the cash receipts go, we're
entering
cash receipts, deposits,
and
cash disbursements.
We're processing checks,
which I will
email you
October's
check register so you can see
the checks that were processed during the month of October.
The journal entries are being made.
Reconciliations
between
the town and the Board of Ed will be in place.
That's working quite well.
Let's see. Payroll is just from PrimePay. We do a journal entry that
that seems to be going well as, you know, everything like I am happy with it at this point.
Every
software system
that you use financially
has some bugs
to work out.
And in my mind, where that is, is in the reporting right now.
So I am working with the programmers to see
if the reports can be produced a little bit better with the columns that
I think should be there, especially the percentage column, which they can't seem to
figure that out, but it is coming, I'm told, in an update
during the month of December.
So that should be okay in place.
There is capability
to export the financial statements to Excel.
So conceivably,
I could do that and add that
final column
percentages
so that, you know, you can have that for
your monthly
financial statement.
The revenue
report
needs a little work.
As far as the balance goes,
I want it to
read as
the previous revenue report, which is
you have the amount that you budgeted or you anticipate
getting,
and then you have the amount that is received.
And I like it to say balance yet to be received
so that, you know,
you know, we got in X,
we need to
receive Y.
So I'm working with them on that.
The
the only other piece is
major for me is the financial statements.
I just get a little frustrated sometimes because
I think as programmers, they can go behind the scenes and fix things easy enough, but I get,
oh, that's in the next update.
So I'll keep
continuing working with them.
The good news is the auditor
likes the
report as far as the detailed transaction.
General ledger, it gives a lot of detail for him to pull
invoices
and
payroll,
journal entries, that kind of thing.
So
he's pleased with that,
which is always a good thing when the auditor likes your software, financial software.
I don't know what more you want me to present, but
I think in eight months time, it's up and running.
And
we are working with it.
It's a
as far as level of security,
there are some things that we have to do extra over and above what we had to do in Phoenix, but that's to be expected.
>> As long as we get used to that, they'll be fine. Can you tell us, I mean, I know it's in the packet, but can you just kind of because I'm not sure exactly how up to date everything is. I know where we're running over on a couple of items.
Are we
are we running over so much at this point that we're outside of contingency? Are we still covered with contingency where we're at right now? We're still covered with contingency right now. There's a few things there's
>> a few things I have to take a look at and
see where we're gonna get the money. But
Is there anything specific?
>> Not
at this time. I'm not prepared to present
something like that right now.
Okay.
Because I have to take a look at at all
departments.
One thing that
comes to mind
is in the
tax collector
department,
where the quality data services software is a little higher than
what was anticipated budgeted.
The assessor
has the same
software
data, quality data services,
and
it was appropriately budgeted at that
amount. So we're good there, but I just have to cover the tax
department
and find the money for that. Is that one contract or two separate contracts? Two separate, one assessor
>> and one.
So
are you telling us that the quality data service information that the tax collector has shows a higher tax collection number
than the assessor's office? Oh, it's a higher cost.
Higher what?
>> Higher cost? It's a higher cost for software services. For the software services. Yeah.
>> And
it could be that we
just didn't anticipate
the right number. I'm not sure. That's why I need to take a look at that. I need to call
quality and see
if there's anything that can be done.
And if it's the correct number, they are two different separate bills.
One's assessor and one's tax collector.
So
that I'm gonna have to research and I don't really have the answer right now as far as
that goes, but I will work with them to see
if there's any kind of
relief,
credit or so forth.
>> I think my
concerns were generally
with all the payroll stuff
because we've had so much shifting in different departments
where we're at if we're running behind or we're okay there.
And then
obviously
public works
where we're sitting, you know, in public works right now.
>> All right. Well, those are the two focus
that I'll certainly
pay attention to and get you that if
>> you can get us something maybe
before the next meeting in the interim, you know, couple weeks out, that might be helpful. Couple weeks out. So when's the next meeting?
Well, we're every month. So yeah, every month. Okay. Alright. It would help if you put my list on it. Put that on my list. Excuse me. Yeah, I I'm sure you got a long list. We're not trying to dump on you. It's just, we're going into budgeting season. And if we're already seeing something that we're off on now, we want to certainly be aware of that as we start talking about department budgets being put together. And that one area may be one of those areas where we have to budget a little higher for.
Yes, exactly.
Well,
>> listen,
it is November
and I realize new software and I realize reporting has been difficult to to get to, but,
we as a board have seen very little.
We need to start seeing it. Don't care if it's outside of the software.
The check registers were helpful to allow us to understand the total amount of transactions
that might go through the department on the TUM level.
And I would ask you from a standpoint of
payroll.
So,
you know, when we do payroll, just so everybody understands here and is dealing with this,
we pay a payroll service to calculate all the payroll. What we're doing internally is making sure the hours are effectively
moved to the payroll service. Is that accurate? Right, yes.
>> We make sure that the amount of hours
are inputted into the system,
time paying their correct,
the rates and so forth,
and
make sure that people who are getting paid are salary people versus
hourly Okay,
>> and then just for the next step, is PrimePay
still processing individual checks for
some of the payroll withholdings?
Very,
yes.
No, direct deposit. I'm sorry.
>> I realized we were trying to get everybody to direct deposit. After
some of the old time
employees have actually
gotten
direct deposit, which is great, what I'm asking is, is the payroll transaction a lump sum transaction
one amount of money that hits the bank account, or do you have multiple transactions?
So all of the gross, like I know PrimePay is paying the federal taxes, but they used to cut for individual
things such as the pension or some of the union dues. Are you still having them cut checks or are they still, or is PrimePay handling all of those transactions?
They are handling all of the transactions to my knowledge. So you're telling me that we have one big lump pulled from our bank account every every two weeks.
>> It's a total amount for the payroll every two weeks. Right.
>> And you make an you're making a journal entry into the system to account for that payroll for that two week period? Yes. Correct. Okay. Including all the deductions.
Okay.
That was it. I wanted to know if PrimePay I mean, I just wanted everybody to understand we use payroll service and I wanted everybody to understand that it should be a
one amount of money broken down into various categories
to make the journal entry.
So all
the payroll goes to the wages for the various departments and Yep. Well,
>> What what's our what we get a payroll journal report,
which is
it gives us all that information on that payroll journal report. That's the report we use to generate the
journal entry and make sure that things are balanced and right,
correct as they should be.
And that's
a very detailed document.
Okay.
>> I do have two
questions.
Do we know if I
had asked this a couple times back and so
I just wanted to make sure I
didn't miss the answer.
Or if Eric knows,
do we have a way with prime with our current time clock system
to punch on and off different jobs?
Like, and I guess this comes up because we just went through this with COVID right so people had all this stuff that they had to do that was maybe COVID related. How do we separate those hours,
but also with public works,
we had a bridge that we repaired.
Did we were we able to punch on and off that bridge work, so that if we did have the ability to apply for for monies during a disaster or something that we can actually show
what we spent to do the repairs,
whether it's tree work or bridge work or whatever, how are we punching on and off jobs? Is there a way to do that with the payroll service? And if, if we don't know if we can get that answer?
>> The answer is no, we can't do that within PrimePay.
You know, if you want to look at that, you're looking at a solution like Workday or,
I mean, there's a bunch of providers
that do that.
My last two jobs,
we did that with,
But,
you know, we don't have that ability right here right now with PrimePay.
>> Is it something that we know of PrimePay offers as well or no?
>> Because the time clocks, the Clan clocks are currently PrimePay, right? Right. They didn't, you know, four or five months ago. I mean, you've asked me this question a couple of times before.
Yeah. I just haven't gotten, I haven't gotten it last couple of months, but as far as I know, no,
>> I've asked that I, he's not within prime pay. I've asked that I hadn't gotten a definitive answer I've gotten. I don't think so. I'm not sure,
you know, I wasn't something we discussed when it was put in. So I just want to know definitively
>> Sherry, can you find out that answer and get it to Adrian before the next meeting?
Sure. I'll have to call them and
It shouldn't be hard.
>> No. I'm sure it's not hard. It's just It's just just gonna be be time to do it and you know. Understand, let's give them the answer.
Thank
you. You're welcome.
>> I
forgot the other question so we're good. Sherry, the
>> reporting,
even if you don't have the system set up to post
revenues,
I would like some type of report next month that shows us what our collections have been in group terms, like how much money did we get from grants, how much money did we sit there and get from tax collections,
some way to at least allow us to understand
the inflow because,
without a balance sheet,
without some type of report to show us where our cash is and where we're at,
that's why we were moving up to a different software. I would like some
additional reporting, and I don't need it to be perfect, Sheri, but what I need it to be is incremental. You need to sit there and give us
pieces and say this is where we're at today, this is where
we've been at, this is where we're moving to, and then we'll at least have information that we can sit there and ask
>> better questions of you in future meetings. Right, so thank you for all your hard work. Greatly appreciate it. If anybody else on this board has some questions, let's go. I remember my other question. What's our total employees on the town side and on the that we're writing checks for to prime? Know, we have to do balancing with how many on the town side and how many on the school side? I have to. I don't know off the top of my head how many employees.
>> Okay, I I just sat today with Marina and we went over payroll for the town side.
Next week, I'll be going over payroll for the board of Edsci.
In total, I don't I'd have to count them up and give you a total. So yeah. Are we based do that. It's just not
>> I don't be available now. You said you you went over you went over payroll with her this this morning or did it take all day I'm I'm trying to get an idea of how much time it actually takes us to do payroll
you know. In the morning it took in the morning. To do this the down okay yeah And would you say it's about the same for the school or a little more? Yeah, about the same.
Okay.
>> Yep.
It's Your in the
better question, Adrian, to move for that is, can you tell us how many hourly employees there are at both locations?
Just so we get an understanding of what's up because- Hourly versus salary? Is that what you're Correct. So split it down because the salary, Adrian, should be nothing. It's just
a
standard amount of money. It gets processed every week.
>> Right.
Much all the same. Well, sorry, I'm working employees. This is the times of the month that we have to take certain deductions out, you know, that kind of thing. Sure. You know, insurance
being one.
So
>> yeah, I can certainly do that. Yeah, I feel more information we get, the better we'll all be.
Okay.
Thank you. You're welcome.
Paula,
any questions?
No? Jeff, you got anything?
Nope. I'm all set. Good to see you. Scott? I'm good.
Okay. Sherry, thank you very much.
>> You're welcome.
I'll get back to you next time and
have some of those reports that you asked for. Check register is
>> really helpful because
that at least gives us an understanding of transactions and it allows us to ask questions like I asked of Eric when I went over it. So
>> I think that's very helpful. That will be forthcoming tomorrow,
October's.
I
>> will have that for you. All right. And next month, if you could sit there and get that in for the package,
that would be helpful.
November transactions.
I mean, doesn't have to be perfect. Just produce it for the November 30,
give it to Amanda or
email it to us before the meeting, and then we can ask questions of Eric during the meeting.
>> So Well, Eric, we'll have to talk about this because I don't I don't think we feel comfortable about sending it through the packet. Fine. Don't send it through the packet. Send it by email. And that's what I'm gonna do tomorrow to to everybody.
Okay.
Alright, thank you. You're welcome.
Alright, thank you.
>> Alright, number five boys and commission presentations. Eric, do we have anything for today?
>> Sure. Apparently, under
item A, the Memorial
Day Committee,
John McCall has asked for some help trying to solicit
additional
members for the Memorial Day committee.
I think we need to kind of put our heads together and figure out who we can Shanghai
into doing that. That would likely be a good,
you know,
good person.
I personally nominate Paula.
So that's my nomination.
>> I nominate Paula she's got enough to do. Paul's got enough to do exactly.
Okay.
>> I help.
I will help get the word out.
Is that what you're asking for? Or you want you're looking for actual committee members?
>> I like both both to get the word out and for actual committee members.
I was being somewhat facetious volunteering you, by the way, I wasn't actually expecting you to say yes, That's usually Adrian's job.
Oh, great. Wow.
So
>> we'll sit there and we'll work on that.
So that was it for board presentations, but under appointments, have the Memorial Day committee, I'm assuming there's no appointments to that committee. No, there are no appointments to that
>> committee at this point.
Under item B.
So, they you probably all saw the letter in the packet
from Diane Brenier asking that you appoint to
alternate members,
allow them to appoint to alternate members,
because it's midseason
per se.
The committees are allowed to nominate
and appoint their own replacements.
>> Yeah, I I think we all read the thing. I I don't think anybody's in any objection to it at all. I mean, we get that they would love a couple of, you know,
backup members and they had some good candidates. So, yeah, why not would do it? Yes. Okay. So, just stop. Before you do that,
>> the charter
has a little something to say about that.
I sent you off a explanation
for that with
the,
with the motions, with my packet motions.
>> Oh. So
it wasn't in the packet. It was in the motions.
>> Well,
the letter was in the packet.
Yeah. But the explanation was in the motions because the explanation came from Dennis.
Basically, it's a charter issue.
Only the town meeting in general
can add alternate members to a committee.
However,
the town's attorney wrote us a legal opinion basically saying that because of the committee we're talking about,
know, in it not having major public implications,
the board of select men
could do a minor ordinance.
And I sent you all the text for the minor ordinance also,
if you so desire,
with the understanding that the next time the town holds a special meeting, it would have to be either upheld or denied at a town meeting.
But for the intermediate
time, you could
you could do it if you so chose at this point.
Next would be legally.
>> Make a motion that we pass the minor ordinance adding two alternate positions to the Norton Fund Commission.
>> Term to be two years run concurrently
with regular members.
>> No. Second that. I'm I'm making a motion
as it is written.
I mean, there's nothing that we're talking about here for terms or anything else. That's how it was written.
Six B. Two years. Got it. Four. Okay.
The
the motion. Whatever. The motion has the ordinance as written.
As written by the town's attorney. Seconded.
Seconded.
Seconded. Discussion?
Alright, all those in favor. Aye.
Aye.
>> Okay, all those opposed, none. All right, so the Norton Commission can appoint two
alternate members.
Okay, a building and land use department administrative assistant.
>> Sure,
I would.
So I've extended a job offer to Lynn Warner and she is accepted.
She's an Andover resident that lives on Gilead as the building department administrative
assistant
>> for twenty hours a week. She interviewed really well. I look forward to accepting that. So I would I would succeed in motion to appoint Lynn Werner of Joliet Road,
and Andover is the building department administrative assistant for twenty hours per week.
I'll second that.
>> Okay, further discussion.
All those in favor. Aye.
Aye.
All right. D assistant town clerk.
>> So
obviously with the Town Clerk out,
there has not been any further progress on
the hiring of an Assistant Town Clerk.
And now item seven, go ahead.
>> Go ahead, Eric. You have you taken a chance to reach out
to the prospective people and let them know that she's out with COVID or and that
just so they're aware they're not, we're not ignoring the situation.
>> Yeah, I have not.
I
actually,
one of the things I wanted to do is reach out to Carol and ask what her plan is for dealing with that. Well, she's gonna address it when she comes back, but she wants to do an in person testing.
I understand, but you have to remember that Carol often does not tell me what she's doing.
And she very well may have already done that. She has not.
>> Okay.
She has not. So. Okay.
In any case, we need to maybe just talk to Carol, but let's not.
We probably should have already reached out to him given the circumstances.
Okay.
Item seven resignations.
Mickey Quagliano,
the cert director.
So Let me just finish writing something down.
>> I did not see the resignation there, but I'm assuming she handed that to you, Eric.
>> Yeah, she resigned
via email. She and I have talked about it a couple of times.
I conned her, not conned her, I recruited her
a couple of years ago,
just before COVID really hit
and she agreed to do it as a very temporary position.
And she finally said, you know what,
temporary
is now.
She did give me another name from one of the CERT team members
that would be willing to do that, I am going to reach out to that person
and have a conversation with them.
I have not done that yet. So,
the moment we don't have
a emergency management director or
emergency management coordinator, I think, technically.
>> Okay,
so we can sit there and we're
all aware that we need a CERT director,
so if anybody finds anybody, please refer them to Eric.
Well, it's actually not a CERT director per se.
>> If
she's resigning as a CERT director, what are we filling?
>> Mickey is resigning, but she's not resigning as the CERT director. She's resigning as the town's emergency management coordinator.
She's still remaining a member of CERT.
She was never the director of cert anyway.
>> Mr. McGuire is saying that because that's,
he's just reading off of the agenda.
I'm not that smart.
Yes,
you are correct.
So you're not that smart.
>> She's resigning. What do we actually do? Need to find someone as the emergency management coordinator?
Yes, yes.
>> Okay. And what about the cert director?
It was just a misprint on our agenda.
Yes,
that was a misprint on the agenda.
>> Did
you reach out to Tom
from Boston Hill Road? I think he subbed in for a little bit there.
>> I have not reached out to him again. I haven't talked to him in a couple of years.
Okay. I talked to him briefly a couple of years ago. Beginning of COVID, right?
Yep.
Okay.
>> It might be worth reaching out, you know?
I mean, he certainly has the skill set.
And, I I can give him a call as well if you want.
He's a neighbor so.
>> Okay.
We're going move on to item eight, the town administrator's report.
Eric?
>> Okay,
so I'm just going to go over a few things. So
part of the
report is incorrect.
For whatever reason, we put the wrong version of it in the packet.
That's on me.
Couple things,
obviously the COVID update is slightly incorrect.
We do have one known case in the town hall.
What five in the town hall?
Not that I know of.
>> No, I killed a mosquito. Had blood on my hand. Oh, okay. Got
>> it. Okay. Was like, yeah, that's
gonna make a comment. I'm like, if you know five employees that have COVID, you know, how come I don't know? Okay.
So
William
Bell is working out really well as a custodian. He's been out painting the gazebo.
The gazebo is coming along nicely.
The building's
cleaner than, you know, I think any of us are used to expecting it.
And as far as I know, the library is fairly happy with that.
Also,
assessors office,
you guys all saw the information
from
the resident who's unhappy with her,
her vehicle
assessment.
If you'd like to discuss that, suggest we do that in executive session,
not in
open session.
In terms of my office, I'm planning on being on vacation December
'6,
and I'll probably be out in Minnesota racing ice boats.
So keep that in mind.
Do you have life insurance?
No.
We put life insurance on you? I'm single.
>> Don't care whether I die. But we can cover you when you're gone.
I got plenty of assets,
>> you know. You keep telling us how dangerous it is, that's all.
Yep.
Eric,
>> stay safe, let's go. Yeah, I will try to stay safe.
So public works, you saw the note we added to the packet regarding the revised load ratings for the bridge. We'll get to that in a little bit.
The
thing I would note is
concern with load ratings was
possible emergency vehicles
like our tanker.
The other thing I would note is that the new federal
transportation
bill got passed.
There was a line
in the news from Connecticut that there'll be up to a billion dollars in culvert
grants to remove, replace or restore culverts and address the flow of water under roads, bridges,
and trails.
So that's something we want to be keeping an eye on, because it looks like that might be a considerable funding
source
going forward.
Looks like sometime after Thanksgiving,
we'll have the initial design meeting with close Jensen Miller, where they're going to present the bridge design info
prior to it going officially before the Connecticut
Department of Transportation.
The surveyors are out surveying, they've been out surveying a couple days,
toe poing in front of the
whole area in town hall for the proposed
community center location.
Construction
is beginning on the connectivity grants, those of you who've gone by on the rail trail have seen the sign is up, they're working on the concrete,
the flat work so the sidewalks.
Not the pavers not the stuff directly in front of the library,
and trying to get that in before the end of construction season
to be taken up again as soon as it warms up again.
So,
in terms of the town hall projects.
I'm not getting really all that far
with the oil storage tank. I asked a couple other contractors because I really have not ever gotten a response
from M and M oil.
So what I did was I went over very carefully the HVAC system
with my tech.
And, we kind of looked at it room by room, did heat calcs on the building?
Know, and then,
you know, we did a bunch of maintenance on the system, which hadn't been done,
you know, at a lot of times, a lot of the air separators were completely
frozen up.
And so we were air bound on some of the registers. So we basically drained everything
and cleaned everything.
And it seems like the heat distribution in the building is at least better.
One of the problems we discovered was one of the thermostats
happens to be right behind beside the fan exhaust
for the building security cameras.
So it was running about six or seven degrees warmer
than,
the thermostat,
which is why that room was never coming on.
So,
I think we've got a partial solution, maybe not a permanent solution.
I'm still working on the other portions of that.
Know, I did get a quote from MG
from Martin to do the masonry,
which was fairly reasonable.
So, I've got to fill in the other portions of that quote, you know, to be able to get it in one big,
you know, pile.
I also met with one of the VoIP
potential suppliers called IP Genie.
They're the Krog vendor. They're also the one in
the
they've got the contract in Hebron Ram
and I think Marlborough
so
hopefully I'll have a quote back from them by by next week.
>> Now, is that our second or third quote on that. That would be our third. We have one more.
>> So I think after that, we really need to sit down and pick a contract and go with it. Absolutely.
It's considerably cheaper than what we're paying now for the landmines.
So there's no rational reason not to do it. And our service
kind of sucks currently.
And then by taking all that off, that also frees up that panel space for a new sub panel.
So I'm trying to get that done fairly quickly.
I would like to
say
that
the
cost for going to VoIP is going to be very minimal.
The other costs associated
with that are low enough.
I actually think we probably shouldn't
apply for low SIP funds for this.
And I think we should just eat this out of the building maintenance fund
and save low SIP for
culverts,
because I suspect that's what we're going to need the next biggest chunk of cash for.
But I wanted to run that by you.
I mean, we can apply for low SIP funds for it. It's just a question
of what your priorities are. Well, I mean, theoretically
>> that
swap out should pay for itself within a year, I would think.
What for VoIP?
>> Yeah. Yeah. VoIP's almost yeah. The hardware costs for VoIP are are fairly minimal. That's not a that's not an issue. I mean, so in in in
>> it may actually depending upon what the numbers come out, it could pay for itself in the remaining budget cycle. So
that that probably is a smart decision.
>> Yes,
I was just talking about low SIP overall
for
because you had asked me to wrap up everything
the town building
stuff,
which was the masonry stuff, VoIP,
replacing the oil storage tank,
and the HVAC and electrical.
And what I'm saying is we're going to bring that cost in reasonably enough
that I think we probably ought to do it out of the existing building maintenance fund as opposed to going for low sick.
That's my only
>> But I also don't have part numbers yet, so. I tend to I tend to believe when you get the numbers, it's going pay for itself maybe in the remaining budget cycle. So that seems to make sense.
The electrical and the other stuff's a different conversation with.
>> Right. And for the record, we did run out of oil again last week on Election Day, which was a bit embarrassing.
At
the same time, fortunately,
when they came out and did the HVAC work,
somebody also flushed enough paper towels down the
good they plugged up the exhaust for for the exit into the tank
>> with paper towels so I had my tech clear that at the same time. Can we remove the paper towels from there and go to a paper towel system? Cause this is not the first time this has happened. Right.
Why is there paper towels down there?
Because Scott, you can't fix stupid.
>> Well, if that's not go there, if there is a solution that does include paper towels, can we do that?
Hand dryers.
Something.
Okay.
Eric, please look at the hand dryers.
>> Well, let's look into something. It may not be hand dryers because that may be cost prohibitive given the electrical requirements, but there's gotta be something else.
We could go to porta potties.
That'll fix them.
>> Yeah. That'll be great for morale. Eric, what else you got?
Let's see.
That's
>> pretty much it unless you guys have specific questions
for me. Most of the stuff is covered elsewhere in other reports.
>> Now
we'll ask you about the time farm or the bridge
at the other section so okay let's let's move on old business
9A Bunker Hill Road
Bridge closure.
>> Wait, back up. Wasn't cart on the list? No, it's the cart thing going, Eric. So
>> I had asked the board a couple times via email whether you guys were interested
in
replacing
the shed roof area.
So right now, cart is being run inside the building whereas before it was in a fenced in
enclosure with the roof on it. I asked
Mr. Reagan to give me a quote for what it would cost
to build it back correctly.
And that includes repairing some of the damage because the one that was there previously wasn't flashed.
And it basically rotted out the siding of the building it was attached to.
To fix the siding,
pour new footings
and
rebuild
a shed wall that meets current building codes
and encloses that fenced in area. It's about $5,000
you know, and I just need your approval if you're interested in doing that. Was one of the items Jeff Murray had put on the list,
>> you know, of the town admin project list for me to review. Jeff, is there any downside to running it or Eric, is there any downside of running it in the building the way we are now?
>> There's not a lot of room with tires.
You know, it's kind of a crowded spot in there with both things going on at once.
>> You say running it in the building,
you're you mean they're sorting in that open space?
>> Yeah, they're sorting inside that existing shed.
It's basically a three sided shed,
that the tires,
and a few other things are stored in.
>> Can we put it? Can we can we put them in the blue building?
One we just put the door on?
>> I mean, you could theoretically,
if you don't wanna use the blue building for something else.
I mean,
whatever you wanna sure. That space is available.
Does that seem reasonable to everyone? Nope. Nope.
>> Maybe we need a sidewalk.
You want to look at it first? Yeah, think that before we make a decision we need to get
some of us down there and look at it. Okay, maybe it's not a good situation as it is.
Saturday?
Sure.
Time?
Eric, can you do Saturday?
Possibly.
>> What time?
What do you want to do with Eric? I
>> mean, I'm
not sure what it is you wanna
Scott would like Everything's there and visible.
>> Maybe it's not. Maybe it's not. The whole setup's not right. Maybe it's wrong. Okay. Here's my John, what time do you wanna do it?
>> And I'll let Paul say something. She's been involved in this more than we have, obviously. So you
did it with Boy Scouts, right?
>> I, right. So I've, I've done CART, so I'm, I can visualize how, how it's gonna work. So I'm just trying to understand
we're, we're fixing
the key
where people drop their stuff off. Is that what we're fixing?
When
they're
doing CART,
obviously, it rains or if it's snowing, they want to overhang to sort. So you're saying the overhang
where the tires are, it's getting cramped in there because the tires are taking up space,
right?
>> Right, because that area is also the tile tire
recycling
area.
So before you had a caged area where everything could get put in.
You know that was a boy scout project at one time. The problem is the roof kept blowing off.
The last time it blew off it kind of got crushed.
So it got thrown in the dumpster.
And there wasn't anything.
They just kind of half baked
built it into the existing fence.
So the question is, if you're going to redo it, you need to do it so that it's structurally suitable and it's going to last for some period of time.
>> Right. So right now when
people drop off their bottles,
they're not putting it in the cage, they're putting it where the tires are?
Correct.
>> So that's why it's tight in there because you have tires,
you have all the stuff for cart, and then they need a spot to sort. Am I understanding that? Correct.
Okay. Correct.
>> So our option is either we fix the cage
correctly,
which Kevin Regan gave us the quote
so that they have space in that underhang so that they can put the when
people drop things off they put it back in the cage or we look for a new area right so those are our two options. Correct.
>> So the blue bill, this blue building, what it, what is it? I'm trying to visualize where it The really big, the really big one to the right of that, that we just put the new garage door on.
>> That would be a really great space because then they can bring their
trash and The store.
>> Thing I'm concerned about that
solution is there's a huge
bee problem in there,
and all we need to do is put a bunch of sugary cans in there, and it's just gonna make the problem worse.
So that's just a suggestion that
there is a lot of wasps and hornet's nests in that building.
>> Yeah, but I mean,
it wasn't a
great situation to begin with when we were doing CART and it was outside because the bees are gonna come in the, whether they're in the building or not. So you are, so you're already dealing dealing with them on the other side.
When it was in the cage. Yeah. I mean, you're, you're pulling out stuff that, you know, you're sorting with sugary drinks.
But how They kept outside.
>> That's why they're outside. That's if they keep inside, it's
gonna be a lot of them. Mean, when we were in there, when we did the renovation for the phase converter, I mean, were all they were all over the place in there.
>> Yeah. So the other question
is,
what are your long term plans
for?
Because I know the board had said initially prior to us putting the door on in the slab there
that you were going to consider at some point
a give and take or some sort of recycling
center there.
Is that still something that you are considering or you're not considering,
because that would make a difference as to what you did with that space.
>> I mean, I guess my my take on it was we're not currently doing that, although we have talked about it in the future.
And I it seemed to me like that would be a perfect space to get them out of the weather if it's you know crappy weather out or whatever, and it gives them plenty of room to work.
I I guess I figured the bees are going to fall no matter where they go, but you know, maybe I'm misunderstanding
that.
>> The tires. Can the tires go on that other building?
What are the?
>> In the blue building? Can I go in the blue building? Think is what she's asking. As soon as you put the something in there, Paul, you're gonna lose that building.
>> It's a good space right now if we ever like if we get a backhoe, we're gonna leave it up there. We ever get a backhoe let's say, okay,
we could park it in that building.
That's what all other towns do, they have their own backhoe at the transfer station so they can pack the thing so they don't have to keep driving the machinery up there.
>> Well, that what we were planning on using that building for? Because right now we're not. We're not using it. Guess, yeah, I mean, down the road we can change it. I I don't think this is a this doesn't have to be permanent, but it's a quick solution for now.
Well?
>> I thought we were discussing this because we're trying to figure out if we're gonna spend the money on fixing the the roof. If we put cart in that building, then
Exactly. Fixing the roof. So we gotta decide, are we spending the money on fixing the roof
or are we gonna move cart somewhere else?
Am I
>> No. You're a 100% right. So, Scott, what time on Saturday?
What time can you make it?
>> I'm traveling back Friday night late. Whatever time you want, Scott. I'll make it on your time.
Are we all going?
>> Well, as many of us that can make it. Who wants to, let's start with this. Who wants to go and do a sidewalk? I'd like to go, but I can't go Saturday. I'm probably gonna be working.
>> I mean, Jeff Murray knows that place. He knows it, you know. Yeah, I'd like to go when Jeff is going. I don't mean to be Maybe not this weekend then. Maybe when Jeff and Paula can both when we all can go at ten or 11:00
in the morning.
>> Schedule it up. 10:00 next week would work for me. I can't do it next weekend. I'm gone.
I'm sorry. I've
gone the whole weekend.
>> The weekend after. Maybe we can email.
Figure it out?
Let's
look at our schedules and we can figure it out from email.
All right, we'll do that.
>> Sorry Eric, it wasn't a quick answer, sorry. My reason for putting that on the list
to begin with was either we're gonna fix it or we had to fix the signs. The signs
at the transfer station said put the cans in the fenced area.
It was either we take the signs down or we fix it just so, because people were still putting cans in the fenced in area it's sad to put them there.
>> Right. No, know.
And that's why,
I
mean, I think it's appropriate to replace
the shed roof if you're going to use that space. It's not really usable now.
It would be usable again with the roof on it, but if you want to consider other buildings, consider other buildings.
Eric,
>> can you send out the scope of work that you had
Kevin give you a number on, please? Sure.
>> Okay. Old business discuss and
act upon the following
nine a Bunker Hill Road bridge closure.
>> So you all saw the engineering
guidance from the state of Connecticut.
>> Okay.
So they're
telling us or your motion was to allow
two way traffic to or one way traffic for all vehicle lanes.
Yeah.
>> So that's right in there, wasn't any restrictions before, there's not any restrictions now,
except for two Yeah,
EV and three
>> so three EV is basically
our water tanker essentially.
It's the only thing that has,
you know,
axle loading high enough to be over the limit.
And Kathy Pelosi had a really good point that Mark or Mike Pelosi who's the director of CART is on this meeting if you wanted to
ask his input.
You could certainly go back one item and do that if you so choose.
>> Why don't we loop? Why don't we loop him into the into the sidewalk?
Rather than going back to the stock and make a decision tonight anyway, so let's have him give us our input in person that might be more appropriate.
>> How do I do it? Mike, just
because it'll be nice. What what is your take on that roof?
>> That
roof out there, chain
link fenced area,
really isn't big enough as it is. We've always had trouble with that. People just end up throwing stuff in there and it makes a damn mess. You can't put enough barrels in there and these guys aim is terrible like that. So then
the car people have to go in there, especially in the summertime, get stung and everything else in there.
So
it's really good where they have some
undercarriage
work they can work out of the rain and the weather
because the building itself that houses the supplies for that is too small to work in,
Way too small. But
we need to,
the ideal thing would be find another place for the tires.
Right, exactly.
>> That's why we should have talked to Mike first. You know what, could we put a conex box in there for the tires at the transfer
station?
Just use a conex box for tires and then we just turn that area into cart.
And that'll leave your price open for a backhoe if you ever get one. That's where we had the old one. The tires don't care where they are. If they go on account, if we just open the doors for and don't we have one down at the ball fields that we could use even?
No, they took it for softballs.
Okay,
yeah.
>> I'm just saying it's a what is it? A couple thousand dollars for a CONEXPOXX?
More
than that right now. Just a small one? Yeah.
Small ones are running somewhere.
>> Can't probably make it this Saturday
because I'm still getting over COVID.
No, I'm
going to take a test on Sunday and they should be clean
so I can go anytime after that.
>> Well, Mike, you look good and you sound good and we're glad you're getting over it. Yeah.
>> And when we have our meeting, Mike, we'll make sure that you are invited.
Okay.
>> All right. Thank you, Mike. All right. Thank you. Okay. And just remember, you're gonna have to get me whenever
you guys decide to meet, you're gonna have to because it will have to be officially noticed
because there'll probably be more than three of you there. So it will be noticed as a board of select and meeting in SiteWalk.
>> We'll let you know.
Alright. Old business.
Back to
Bunker Hill Road
Bridge.
What are we going to do? Are we making a motion to expand the
opening of that bridge?
What's the board's appetite for it?
>> I'm fine with one lane in both directions with no rate restriction if other people are. But I still wanna leave it as one lane right now.
Okay. Scott?
I'm fine with that.
>> Okay. So I would motion authorize public works to open Buckle Hill Bridge
to all traffic with no rate restrictions. It will remain a one lane bridge open to traffic in both directions.
I'll second that.
>> All right. Further discussion?
All those in favor? Aye. Aye.
All those opposed? No. Okay.
9B,
the RAM multi use turf field project. I'm assuming Eric gets on here to
say that it was solemnly defeated in all three towns.
Okay.
All right. It failed.
It failed. All right. 9 C Veterans Monument Park upgrades flagpoles
battle cross and irrigation system. Where are we at with those items?
>> Okay,
so the irrigation
system is in
the
water system,
and the plumbing portion is tied in
and done the low voltage lighting is done.
And all the electrical is done. We're disconnected
from
the transformer,
the unmetered connection, and we are connected and running through the Andover,
museum
at this point.
So for the stuff that the town had agreed to pay for,
we're pretty much completed everything
that the town had agreed to.
The only area that's of contention is Jerry asked whether the town will be willing to pay for the cost
of the low voltage lighting that was installed
and was moved around,
which the total bill for that is
2,180
something like that dollars.
And
I told Jerry that because
the Board of Selectmen hadn't authorized
that I didn't feel like
I should really exceed the scope of that project, that it should be a board's decision whether he wanted to fund that or leave that to Jerry to fund.
Do we have any idea?
>> Looks like 2,118
is what it was, right, Eric? Correct.
I mean, we did give a scope of work. I'm not sure how we ended up outside of that.
And did we get competing bids on that? Or was that just something that was done as part of the projects?
>> Well, was done as part of the project.
I mean, part of what happened is we had an agreement
at the last minute
for
what would have been the most expensive item, which was the installation of the topsoil
and
seeding,
Andover landscaping and another contractor
agreed to do that, you know, essentially for free.
We worked everything else around that.
So,
you know, I didn't really have anything to do with
the low voltage lighting.
That was what Jerry had wanted to put in.
Do we have the money anywhere?
>> We're
already running tight. That's the problem. We're already, we're running into other
areas where we're, we're going to be tight.
That was my conversation with, that's why I was asking Jerry where we're at, because we have some other issues.
>> I mean, I don't know where Jerry is on the funding for the other the Battlefield Cross and any of the rest of that
because that was not part of the scope of anything I did.
>> So I can give a quick update I talked, I talked to Jerry yesterday or the day before.
What
was the question. Okay.
So the flagpoles
are ready to go. Those are covered. He has enough money for those.
As far as I remember from our conversation, the Battlefield crossed and then he had another
monument.
I guess the bases are in, but he's waiting to order the actual top pieces because he has to
raise some more money. Things got doubled in price and it was hard for him to
get these where he wanted to with his original price. So those are on hold right now. Right. He can't get them anyways.
>> I
mean, I, I just,
I feel like we gave a scope of work and we need to stick within the scope of work. That's my own take on it. It's not,
it's not, it's not a slight on anyone or anything.
Certainly not on the vets being one of them. I just feel like as a town,
you know,
We we've allowed a citizen to
put all of his energy and effort into this, and we've I feel like we've been really supportive of this,
but.
It can't be something where we just let them step outside of that,
you know.
>> So just so I understand the light, the lighting we're talking about that he he's asking us to cover, is it
has it been put in or it's it's operating
>> as of I saw it when we
drove over the weekend. So yeah,
>> because the lighting had to be in before you put the topsoil in.
Alright.
>> So this is something that happened several weeks ago.
Before the before the grass was even planted.
>> So what happens? Do we know?
This is obviously a question for Jerry. But Eric,
if if we don't agree to pay for this, he's gonna does he have the funding somewhere? Or we don't know?
>> I don't know.
I mean, you know, we had to. He's
>> trying to check his books right now. Carol's out, so he can't
see.
>> He doesn't know exactly how much money he has. Well, think what I think this I think the point would be that it might put him further behind on the other monuments that he wants to add down there would be my best guess,
>> you know.
Eric,
do we have money from some other things that have been
manipulated?
>> So I gave you guys a
breakdown,
you know, of where we are with funding for that.
So
bear with me for a sec. This is a little convoluted.
>> Page was that
in the packet so we can all jump there?
Well, just share your screen, Eric.
>> All right, let me track it down here.
Can I share screen Amanda?
>> I think it's
it looks like it's page 28 of 80 on the packet. 28.
>> Okay,
so,
I'll give you the rundown because this is kind of convoluted.
Initially, you authorize the use of all the excess COVID relief money, which was about $24,000
in the second allot.
So, the way it worked is the state required us to put that money towards public safety.
So we credited that money to the resident state troopers account because that was the biggest public safety line we had. And then we transferred all the excess money after we paid that bill back out of that fund into the building maintenance fund.
So,
the
total of that,
that we transferred back out of the resident troopers account was, was just over $44,000
because the resident trooper himself
came in under budget about $20,000
I was not anticipating we were going to
transfer
in the whole $44,000
That was a miscommunication
between myself and
Sherry, but having put it in the building maintenance fund, I thought that was a fine place
because we certainly got plenty of building maintenance stuff
to do with it.
So
as far as
the monument expenses,
you know that this is the stuff we've actually spent for at this point.
So
we're over the $24,000
allotment,
but that includes the electrical work, the low voltage lighting by one.
If we take that out, we're pretty much, you know, we're just over the 24,000
in the account.
So
that's where we are in terms of that whole project.
>> And
could explain to everybody in the board about Lenco electrical and how much money they donated also.
>> So
Lenco
comped us about half the total bill for the electrical work.
He basically charged us,
you know, no markup on parts.
And then,
you know, he,
yeah,
very little on labor.
So
I don't know whether I sent you guys the full bill. The total bill for Lenco was about 21,000
something,
but he comped us about 11,000 out of the work.
>> So, and so that 21,000
was what that's the new,
a new service up there?
>> Yeah.
That was everything related to the electrical work there.
Okay.
So,
>> and one of the things that's really difficult
is we're connecting to a building built in the, you know, 1800s,
and that we're trying not to affect
the aesthetics of the building as much,
you know, as we absolutely had to.
So,
I don't know if you've ever seen the access into the basement.
But basically what they do is they remove one of the heating ducts.
They push the duct out
and they climb through the duct opening to get into the basement.
And I can tell you, I'm sure as hell not going into the basement in that. I don't think I would fit.
It's just an enormous amount of labor.
When I was out there and they were working on that thing
for a hell of a long time.
>> My take on this is that everyone
that's involved
really did a lot of extra
and I don't believe that $2,118
is a lot to ask and you can get a lot of goodwill for just paying it and not and
be done with it.
>> Again, I my only concern is that are we setting a precedent,
on these types of things?
>> You know, Adrian, Adrian, the project is
complete.
It's it's finalized. It's
>> not complete. Let Scott make the motion to approve it. Let's go. There you go.
>> I make I make a motion to approve the $2,118
for the low voltage lighting to Ron's professional lawn care.
>> Okay.
I'll second that. Further discussion?
Where was the motion that Eric had just for just for fun to look at?
No. I'm missing it. 10
d 10 d.
>> 10 d.
Okay.
So further discussion? No? No. All right. All those in favor?
Aye.
All those All
>> those opposed?
All those abstain?
Okay. Adrian, where is Jeff Murray? Did he vote? Because I can't see him. Yes, he voted.
He voted for it? Yes. Yes.
All
>> right. So four zero one. All right. Let's move on
to
10, new business discussed next month.
10A, town wide Christmas caroling. Paula,
what do you got for us? Okay,
>> so
there's a rec commission meeting tomorrow night.
Adrian and I are gonna go and talk to them. I've talked to Carol about this and
we kind of have our ducks in a row now and
we're going to talk
to the rec commission tomorrow night and see if we're going to be updating anything.
So we have our date. We're talking about Saturday,
December 18.
We've contacted some organizations to come join us
and
we're going to talk to the rec commission about doing some
hot cocoa and treats and things like that.
We're going to start promoting this to the public probably next week, just as a save the date.
We've contacted CERT and
the firehouse.
So everybody's been very
>> supportive and positive about it. Now we just have to get our details in and, you know, there's, there's a bit of concern that from cert that the weekend that we picked is too close to Christmas.
So we're still trying to
figure out if we need to change that. Their concern is that they won't get people to cover,
the safety side of it. So,
we'll have to square up.
>> I think once, once we, once we talk to them and have a meeting with them give them the details, then we'll know better. But they did say
that they weren't sure about people's schedules. But we're going to have a meeting with CERT in the firehouse
and get those
details figured out.
>> Okay.
All right. Thank you.
10B,
Personnel, Building and Land
Use Department,
>> and the Assistant Town Clerk position. Eric? I think we've already discussed these. We don't need to discuss them again. Let's go. Okay.
10 C policy on snowplow
damage and mailbox replacement.
>> That was in your packet. That was a slight revision
of
the,
policy that you approved a couple of years ago.
Not a significant revision.
So why are we revising it?
>> Jay wanted to add a couple of things
that he felt was appropriate.
Can you highlight them for the public please?
That's everything that's in bold.
>> And
since we're up, if we agree to update this, are we sending out
information
saying check out our website and
read this for updates? Or how are we
letting them know that there are potential updates?
>> Just already, we already publicized this frankly.
I was just giving this to you
since it was already largely approved by you.
Didn't think you guys really needed to formally approve this again.
You know, but we can certainly
do so.
>> I would say, wait, I would say my suggestion,
let's wait until it's snow time because this is going to come up as a conversation.
So
we'll put a post out there and
or email whatever we think is appropriate.
So for snowfall, you're gonna
get phone calls.
>> Well,
we will repost it
then. There's no question.
But the fact of the matter is,
if you wait until the first snowfall,
the ground is hard. And if your mailbox is not where it should be,
then
it's already too late.
And the point is, is that there's a very specific spot relative to the road that a mailbox should be in.
And that's because
you shouldn't be able to hit a mailbox with the plow if you're plowing all the way to the curb.
That's really what
you know if you wait till then, I'm actually asking public works to have all the plow drivers
go their routes
and put
tape to everybody's mailbox
one of these alerts if it's a mailbox
that doesn't meet it's either too far back or too close to the road.
You know, because there's a bunch of mailboxes
that legitimately
are likely to get hit during normal plowing operations if we're plowing all the way to the curb.
>> So are we going have those guys sign off that they've done that? They've tagged their whole route.
>> So I talked to Jay about that. We haven't come up with a formal plan to do that, but I do want to come up with a list of everybody whose mailboxes I don't intend to replace if they get hit. Well, I mean,
>> you've just told us that there's a bunch of them. Then let's get a plan in place and do it. Let's not
do it. Dolly, dolly. You just said it has to happen before the gets any ground gets any colder.
>> So let's do it, you know? Has Mr. Murray's box been tagged?
>> Not yet. It's definitely in the wrong spot. I've seen his. It's way too close to the curb. No, it is not. It's actually
>> no. To be honest with you, I'm on a sweeping curve and the plow always tends to drift wide every time I put the reflective Sweeping things curve
that sounds good. If put the reflective things up marking the curve we don't have a problem it's just we had early snowfall when one guy hit And it's very, in
the public works defense,
it's very hard to find the edge of the roadway on my street.
>> Well, can. They just listen till they hear your, once they hit your box, they know where it is. Got a brand new one this year. It's right
>> for picking.
I filled mine with concrete, put the pole 10 feet in the ground. I'm dying to let the state hit mine. I've actually moved mine up back. I moved it back four inches from the edge, so it's back farther than it was in previous years. Oh, so it might've been closer than when it got hit. It was at the edge of the curbing before.
>> At the edge of Must be eight inches back, Jeff. Oh, so he's four inches too close. Better tag it, Eric, just in case.
>> Okay,
so much for fun. So Eric, you're going to sit there and have Public Works do that and
publicize it now.
Does anyone here have a problem with
the information?
No. It's good information.
>> No, I just want to make sure we have the information. We're talking about doing it. Let's follow-up on it.
>> Okay,
so now we're moving on to
10D Veterans Memorial
Field Funding
Agreement and the Rich Calarco
Field Maintenance
Proposal.
Eric?
>> All
this agreement is, is it's
changing
how we are actually paying
Rich Calarco.
Used to be, we used to pay Hebron
directly and now we're going to be paying
Rich Clarko
directly.
So that's gonna come off the Hebron budgeted amount.
Right.
Yep. Okay.
And Hebron's okay with this?
>> Yeah, yeah, it's the same, same. He's working for them also, Adrian.
>> No, I'm just given that we're changing and we're paying, I just want to make sure everybody's on the same page at all.
Yeah. Eric, you look confused.
>> You know, I haven't physically spoken. I personally haven't spoken to Andy or Parks and Recs
to see. I know that they are subcontracting.
Hebron is subcontracting
directly
with Corko again, also
himself.
So it's just a question of whether we subcontract with them directly or we subcontract with them through Hebron or subcontracting
with them. I don't think it really makes a whole hell of lot of difference myself.
Well, unless Hebron was taking a percentage.
>> Can you
find out from Hebron if they're understanding that their total bill will be reduced by 1,600
and some odd dollars?
>> I don't think it's $1,600
I think it's more I like
>> thought it was. That was a yearly price. Was it a yearly price?
Yeah, I thought $20.23
>> something I think. Let's just clear the air so that everybody's on the same page, please. Yeah, it's $11.50
dollars for the first year.
>> That's because it's only a short
that's a season. Short season, yeah.
And the whole year price was double that.
Okay.
All we really need to do is do what Jeff McGuire said and call them and talk, make sure you talk to them and if they're on the same page as us. Yeah. Right.
>> All right.
So let's move on to the American Red Cross donation bin request
10E.
I saw it in our package. Where is that going to try to be put?
I have no idea.
Who put it in our package?
>> It's
just a request from the Board of Selectmen for a clothing donation spot.
They're asking Okay. Us like they put
>> they have no idea where to put one. They're just asking us.
>> Okay, sure. And what are they proposing to put there? A bin or something?
Yes. It's
>> in the package. It's one of their metal. Don't they already put their don't they already have a bin in town?
Not that I know of.
>> I thought there was something over by the post office.
Mean they have They're
>> hopping on to explain. So the contact reached out. They currently have one at the Shell station. So you've probably
seen it there
and Shell wants them to move it.
So they reached out to see if the town
has a location for them.
Any recommendations,
anyone?
>> I mean, I would put it at the dump. That's where we have the rest of them.
Is
there room at the transfer station?
We'd fit it in somewhere.
Okay.
>> The only problem with that it's going to limit access to when to transfer
station days.
Is this all do we know does this compete with
the Andover
collections that the pantry does?
No.
I have no idea.
>> This is, it looks like it's just clothes.
So
I'm just reading the email.
>> No, I just know in the past they've done clothes as well.
>> Know? Oh, they do their, yeah, they do their clothing drive. I think
twice a year.
This
would be sitting out there
the entire year.
>> Why don't we sit there and push this to next meeting and sit there and see if there's an appropriate spot in town if anyone finds a room from the church, the library, the field.
We
can talk if there are reasonable spots and there are probably
some and some that we would rather not do them at.
So Let's
find out if it might work. Amanda,
one thing, ask them
if we potentially staged at our transfer station, would two days a week
be acceptable
Just to get information, not saying that we need to put it at the transfer station, but we might as well ask.
Eric,
10F, the connectivity grant construction progress. You talked about it before, do we need to talk about it again?
No, we're starting in on the sidewalks for that.
>> Eleven, approval of minute meetings for Tuesday, 10/12/2021,
special meeting minutes.
Everybody
read those minutes. We all good. So we wanna make a motion.
>> Make a motion to accept the minutes as so written.
Second.
>> Second. All those in favor,
aye.
Aye. Opposed? No. Okay.
Got nothing.
Finance twelve, finance department report we went over 13.
Well, does anyone have any questions on the information that's in the package? It looks like we got a final report from last year off of Phoenix and then we got a report for this year
off of the new system.
Eric, a question. I didn't ask Sherri, but I asked you.
Are you getting an accounts payable report
or are we just cutting checks the day we receive the invoice of the bills as we have in the past?
Like I look at this and nothing
encumbered, so I'm just wondering, are you getting any payables? Anything?
>> I don't know about an accounts payable report.
I mean, get a giant stack every two weeks,
you know, and I review them before we cut checks. I review them and sign off on them before we cut checks.
Okay. I don't get a report per se.
>> I mean, in Sherry's defense, though, she did bring up, did say that that's something she's working on to get us, payables and receivables.
I'm just wondering if
he sees them. I know we don't. I just asked the question if Eric saw.
>> So Eric, you basically see the bills. You get a stack of bills. Those bills get input into the system and checks get covered.
Sure.
Anybody have anything they want to talk about with the finance department reports?
>> I can jump in while I'm here. So I have, and I don't know if any of you guys want these or if it's an appropriate copy, I print the check registers every time that's what Eric is on the top of Eric's pile.
I don't know if including those in like the agenda, the meeting packet is helpful
for you guys like each month or?
>> We
have asked for those and those are those on a monthly basis will be included. Mean, don't necessarily know we need to see them every week. But yes, it's very helpful to understand for the people that aren't at the the time signing the checks to see what the checks were cut for. And then we can ask appropriate questions. Yeah. Think Sherry said she's gonna send them outside of the Yeah. Package. Okay. Email them to us outside of the package.
Okay.
So 13 budget.
Eric, are there any appropriation transfers? Not at this point, no.
Any over expenditure requests.
Not at this point.
Okay, item 14 tax collectors report,
there is a refund request.
Where did I see? I wanted to go over that with everybody just so everybody understands why I'll vote no.
So it's on page 65
of your packet.
>> There were two pages though when I looked at it this morning.
No, not that one.
Oh, it's in the assessor's report. That's where I saw it.
Okay.
So
of those refunds,
There were sold ones and then the Board of Assessment Appeals
made three adjustments,
all for vehicles.
All right.
>> Anyone wanna make a motion on that one? The one thing I would say before you make motion
is that there's a strong possibility.
The top one, the one to the Honda lease trust,
you know, end up in litigation at some point.
So I'm not saying don't prove it as is,
but I'm saying if you do approve it, know that that's maybe headed for further court action.
From us or from someone else?
From somebody else.
>> All right, wait, back up again. You're saying if we approve it as it stands?
>> It doesn't matter whether you approve it or not.
That doesn't have any bearing on any
further.
>> What are you trying to tell us? Just tell us. So
>> if you wanna discuss that, I would say we discussed that in executive session.
>> Well, I mean, already got an FYI on it, so what's the difference?
>> That's the same one, right? If you wanna discuss it, discuss it in executive session.
>> Okay.
So does someone wanna make a motion to approve these?
>> Want to go to executive session now and figure out why we're not talking about it in public.
>> We
can move on. I hate approving tax refunds.
Anybody? We'll
circle back to it after executive session.
>> Excited about that.
The assessor's report.
Anybody have any questions?
Eric,
when is the, for the town and the residents, when is the
revaluation
for all of the residential properties being posted?
>> So the goal is to have that posted at the beginning of December.
>> Okay.
Any other questions or any other issues related to that?
All right.
So we're going to go on a 16,
departmental report.
Fire
department.
department report was included.
Didn't see anything from the burning official,
>> trip K, residency trip. There was a burning official. The burning official's
>> report is in there. It was out of I apologize.
Anybody have any questions about any of these?
Library,
assessors,
senior transportation?
>> Thank you, Jasmine. A lot of burning on Bunker Hill. It's all I noticed.
>> There's more than this or
what are you saying to us Scott?
It's just an observation.
>> Just an observation. Okay. Does it does it jive with the, with the
burning officials report? I'm going by the official report.
>> Okay. I thought you were saying something over and above. Yeah. There's
>> a total of
six total permits issued for
this fiscal year 2021.
Three on Bunker Hill.
Glad to see people cleaning up their property.
>> I'm glad to see it too. Two for the same individuals.
>> So that's good. All right.
Okay.
Processor's
report.
And that was it. So that's all that was in the package.
We did get one from the registrar of voters. So
senior transportation registrar of voters, thank you for the registrar of voters for running a
seamless election
of a one question ballot
on November 2. It's appreciated.
Correspondence,
nothing. Public speak. Alright, let's go.
Diane Greiner.
>> No, I'm all set. Thank you very much. Always entertaining.
>> As
always, Diane. Diane Scherquette?
Diane all set. Thanks. Thank you. Joanne Ebert?
Thank you. All right.
And Marina,
if you'd like to public speak.
No?
I'm good for right now. Excellent.
>> All right. So
we now have
item 19 executive session
to discuss the Assistant Treasurer's Officers Union Contract
pay and benefits.
>> I gotta figure out how to share my screen. No,
>> no, no, no, no. That's not yet. We have to vote to go in. Oh, sorry. I'm waiting for someone to make a motion. I don't know how this works. That's okay. Make a motion that we go into executive session.
>> I make a motion to enter executive session per
CGS
one-2026A
to discuss the assistant finance officers union contract.
I would also like to invite the following members. Who do we want to invite?
>> Well,
first of all, I will second that.
Marina,
as an employee, you have the option of having this as a public conversation, would you rather have an executive session.
Yes, I'd rather have an executive session.
>> Then I would like to invite Diane Chalkat into that conversation, as well as the Board of Finance representatives.
Would you also like to have Eric Anderson?
I would as
a line supervisor, please.
I'll second that.
Okay. Well, who's making the motion? Paula or Adrian?
>> I made the motion and I think Adrian seconded. I seconded it and Scott modified it to include Eric.
>> Okay.
All those in fair?
All those opposed?
All those that abstain?
Okay, let's go.
Let's move this into executive session. We appreciate everybody else for joining us. Thank you very much. Amanda, if you can pass along the
controls to Paula
and we can stop the recording. We can go into executive session and then when we come out, we'll get it all started again.
Is Nick still on?
>> Nick is usually sitting there so we're going to have to drop him when someone gets control.
Okay.
Give me one second here.
>> We've got everybody we need. I'm going
to pause the recording or stop it rather.
Either one.